julien.battaglia@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/julienbattaglia/

415-430-8070 • Dallas, TX 75240

Certified actuary with 15+ years' experience in financial engineering, data analytics, and financial consulting across renewable energy and international insurance companies. Polyglot with strong communication and administration skill supported by a positive and outgoing attitude. Proven history of success with contract negotiations, technical solutions, and problem-solving.

Areas of Expertise include:

- Profit Improvement
- P&L Management
- Strategizing
- Financial Policy

- Budget Administration
- Accounting
- Auditing
- Teamwork

- Budget Forecasting
- Strategic Planning
- Regulatory Compliance
- Actuary Sciences

Professional Experience

Freelance Consultant • San Francisco, CA • October 2015 to February 2019

Educate clients on financial problem-solving, statistical process control, data analytics, financial calculations, reporting, price forwards curve (PFC), and regulatory compliance. Collaborated with data scientists and developers to create trading system based on machine learning, chart patterns, risks management, and portfolio management.

Key Accomplishments:

- Calculated PFC used by client for financial forecasting report; attained probability value of less than 0.05.
- Executed trading system with performance rate of 17% since 2015 with a broker account, conducted workshops.
- Created highly-advanced financial management Excel files for multiple clients; reported time savings exceeded 50%.

Executive Director • SD Single Family Office • Cologny, Switzerland • September 2014 to October 2015

Negotiated real estate transaction for \$15+M home; orchestrated capital improvements. Strategized financial investments and coordinated with private banks for short- and long-term assets allocation based on risk aversion. Organized travel, finances, assets, education, and personal affairs; managed estate employees.

Key Accomplishments:

• Leveraged negotiation acumen to reduce home contract price by \$3M; achieved return on \$150M in capital at rate of 10+% with very low risk tolerance.

Software Package Manager • FMV SA • Sion, Switzerland • September 2007 to August 2014

Spearheaded business processes to oversee electricity management system using Robotron based on Oracle database. Manipulated MS Excel VBA tools to increase proficiency for financial and grid system managers, data transfers, and Swiss national grid regulator.

Key Accomplishments:

- Architected system to manage financial and power data for 12 electricity plants and 20+ B2B clients; won large option contracts based on Black and Scholes Option calculations; saved 10% on European market contracts using price forwards curve projection.
- Authored 200 page standard procedure manual for managers and mentored 10 users to expert level.

Additional experience as **Actuary** with Axiomtec Software SA in Lausanne, Allianz in Bern and Aon Hewitt in Zurich, Switzerland and **Associate Financial Consultant** with VZ AG, Zurich, Switzerland.

Education & Credentials

Master of Science in Actuary | HEC Lausanne • Lausanne, Switzerland

Certificate of Advanced Studies in Marketing Management and Communication | HEC Lausanne • Lausanne, Switzerland

<u>Certificates</u>: Certified Actuary, HEC Lausanne <u>Languages</u>: Fluent in French, Italian, and German

<u>Technical Proficiencies</u>: VBA, C++, Python, Oracle <u>Community Involvement</u>: SPCA Volunteer, Keen Sport Coach